当你从未受过伤时  战斗很容易
It's easy to fight when you've never been hurt before.
在那之前  你不可战胜
Until it happens, you're invincible...
但每次战斗都有风险
But with every fight, there's a risk,
有时你会因为受伤而退出
and sometimes you're sidelined.
当你不知道何时才能恢复时
The road to recovery is long--
恢复之路很漫长  没有尽头
endless when it's not clear if you can recover.
有些日子  我会忘记自己是谁
Some days, I lose sight of who I am,
但我忘不了我的任务
but I can't forget what my mission is.
鲍勃
Bob.
镇静  鲍勃
Easy, easy, Bob.
再高点
Higher.
再高点  好的  鲍勃
Higher, higher. Okay, Bobby.
看着点
Watch it, hey!
我必须保持希望
I have to keep the hope alive
冷冻人在做准备
威尔福德有动作
我仍然能改变现状
that I can still make a difference.
如果不行的话
If not...
那死而复生又有何意义
Then what was coming back from the dead for?
我数着日子  祈祷能恢复到从前的样子
I count the days and pray to be whole again,
跟我在雪国列车上的朋友团聚
back with my people on Snowpiercer,
1034节车厢
1,034 cars long.
雪国列车
第二季 第五集
"保持希望"
我们从雪国列车回来后
He hasn't stopped playing her
他就一直在放她的歌
since we got back from Snowpiercer.
雪国列车
Snowpiercer--
那是
that was
我这辈子度过的最棒的一天
the only best day of my life.
他疯了
He has lost his mind.
你看他让我们读什么了吗
Do you see what he has us reading?
奥德丽小姐太耀眼了
You know, Miss Audrey was so dazzling.
他思念着她  他的爱人
He's pining for her, his great love.
而你一直念着倒数第二个澳大利亚人
And you've been pining over the second-to-last Australian.
-他叫默里  -默里
- His name's Murray. - Murray.
《蝴蝶梦》
亲爱的读者
Dear readers,
放下你的书  为读书俱乐部磨练你的妙语
lay down your tomes and sharpen your bon mots for book club.
-你知道这意味着什么  -靠  我还没看完
- Yes, you know what that means. - Shit, I haven't finished!
他杀了他第一任妻子  房子烧毁  走吧
He killed his first wife and the house burns down. Let's go.
你和威尔福德发生了什么
What happened with you and Wilford?
你想谈谈吗
Do you want to talk about it?
我在这工作时  你救了我
When I worked here, you saved me.
你知道怎么拯救自己
You knew how to save yourself.
拜托  是我
Come on, it's me.
我对你和威尔福德之间的事知之甚少  这让我很担心
The little I do know about you and Wilford has me worried.
我的眼睛睁得很大
My eyes are wide open.
这跟上次不一样
This is nothing like the last time.
我不会有事的
I'll be fine.
小心点
Just be careful.
海德伍德医生  海德伍德医生
Dr. Headwood, Dr. Headwood.
艾美莉亚
Emelia.
刮了胡子的达米安
Damien with the nice, trim jib.
艾莉克斯  来吧  大家都来
Alex, come in, all of you.
谁想先来说说你对《蝴蝶梦》的想法
Who wants to open with thoughts on our "Rebecca"?
嗯  你想来吗
Yeah. You?
不
No?
你
You?
来吗
Yeah?
那就别举手
Then don't put your hand up then.
我觉得她
I found her devotion
对她丈夫的热爱很可悲
to her husband tragic.
坦白说  她丈夫很垃圾
Mm. Her husband sucked, frankly.
他很垃圾
He sucked?
这个英语文学里最经久不衰作品之一里的
This husband from one of the most enduring works
丈夫
in English literature?
艾美莉亚
Emelia, what about you?
你相信我们的旁白女主人公吗
Do you trust our narrator heroine?
我们对她几乎一无所知
We know almost nothing about her
只知道她年轻  坠入了爱河
other than she's young and in love,
但我们能体会到她的心态
but we do get into her psyche,
体验  她有多嫉妒瑞贝卡
experience how jealous she is of Rebecca.
如果她不诚实的话  我想
If she wasn't being honest, I don't think
她不会给我们展示她的缺点
she would show us her ugly traits.
嗯
Yeah, mm.
但这是忽视了她脑子完全被瑞贝卡占据的事实
But that's ignoring how consumed she is by Rebecca.
如果她不信任自己
If she doesn't trust herself,
那我们为什么信任她
then why would we ever trust her?
有道理
Excellent point.
艾美莉亚  你的反驳
Emelia, your rebuttal?
她恋爱了
She's a girl in love.
这能让她做出疯狂的事
That can make you do crazy things
行事异常
and act outside of yourself.
失陪
I beg your pardon.
你们继续讨论
Do continue with the salon.
我认为
Well, I, uh, I find
他们这一对很浪漫
the pair of them romantic.
-他们的爱情高于一切  -不  绝不是
- Their love above all else-- - No, absolutely not.
我觉得这让人沮丧
I find it quite depressing.
我们在前列车厢的朋友点灯了
Our friend uptrain lit a lantern.
可以行动了
We're a go.
干得漂亮  塞克斯
Good work, Sykes.
把这封请帖送去给奥德丽
Now, send this invitation out to Audrey.
迷人的奥德丽小姐
我盛情邀请你  在穿越拉萨的紫禁城时与我共进晚餐
一个充满回忆  满是忠诚的地方
去大爱丽丝的请帖
It's an invitation to Big Alice.
你真幸运
Oh, well, lucky you.
我盛情邀请你  在穿越紫禁城时
A cordial invitation to dine together
-与我共进晚餐  -还有西藏
- as we pass the forbidden city. - But also Tibet.
我们多年前去过那里
We traveled there years ago.
这是个很大的请求
We're asking an awful lot of you.
你能行吗
You good with this?
我理解  我们需要保护自己
I understand. We need to protect ourselves.
前提是你能保护自己
Only if you can protect yourself.
你怎么知道他不会把门一锁  把你留在那
How do you know he won't just lock the door and keep you there?
约瑟夫不会违背我意愿强留我
Joseph wouldn't hold me against my will.
他不是这种人
It's not his way.
而且我们需要这样做  我能做到
And we need this, and I can do it--
至少搞清楚那边的情况
at least find out what's going on over there.
-这是个通讯面板  -只有一颗螺丝
- This is the comms panel. - It's only got one screw.
在大爱丽丝上  是个红盒子
On Big Alice, it's a red box
就在他后面引擎的墙上
attached to a wall in his back engine.
原型里有个缺陷  不过我们的修复了
There was a flaw in the prototype fixed in ours.
你把这两根线交换位置
You switch these two wires,
我们就能听到他说的一切
we can hear everything he says.
他不会知道自己的通讯设备开启还是关闭
He won't be able to tell if his comms are turned on or off.
给我留点
Hey, save some for me.
还多着呢
Plenty where that came from.
我们已经好久没有遇到
It's been quite some time since we've had a patient
组织损伤如此严重的患者了
with this amount of tissue damage.
能愈合吗
Will it heal?
海德伍德夫妇  借一步说话
Headwoods, a moment?
就是今晚了
It's happening tonight.
这不是我们说好的
That wasn't what we agreed on.
注意  门向内打开
你的惊恐症犯了  放松
You're having a panic attack. Relax.
说出房间里的五样红色物品
Name five red things in the room.
什么  什么
What--what?
说出房间里的五样红色物品  赶紧
Name five red things in the room, quick.
血液  血液
Blood, blood.
组织
Tis-tissue.
-桶  -接着说
- B-bucket. - Keep going.
按钮
B-button.
书
Book.
你的红书
Your red book.
诀窍在于将痛感外化
The trick is is to externalize the pain.
别内化  否则会让你瘫痪
Don't internalize it, or it'll paralyze you.
谢谢
Thank you.
威尔福德今晚计划了什么
What's Wilford planning for tonight?
海德伍德夫妇看起来不开心
The Headwoods don't look to pleased.
别
Don't.
你惹不起他们
They are not people you wanna cross.
我们今天得先麻醉你
We'll have to put you under for the debridement
给你的肩膀做清创
on your shoulder today.
我们得再深入
We have to go deeper.
我们的11号气象气球今早放出去了
Okay, so our weather balloon number 11 went up this morning.
那真是好消息  德拉托雷先生
Well, that's good news, Mr. De La Torre.
可以和梅兰妮建立联系时告诉我们
Let us know when we can announce contact with Melanie.
她的砰砰声能振奋士气
Her pings do wonders for morale.
-抱歉  -哈维  你刚才说到哪了
- Sorry. - Javi, you were saying?
对  数据已经分享给威尔福德了
Yeah, so the data has been shared with Wilford
像我们之前同意的那样  梅兰妮能保证结果安全
as we agreed. Results are safe with Melanie.
科学安全  但我们不是
The science is safe, but we are not.
我得知道哪些车厢容易受到外部袭击
I need to know which cars are vulnerable to an outside attack.
有迹象显示威尔福德的冷冻人
There are indications that Wilford's cold man
-可能另有打算  -什么迹象
- might be up to something. - What indications?
维修车  任何有舱门的地方
Breach cars, anything with a port
-都可能是弱点  对吧  -对
- might be a weak point, yeah? - Yeah.
我们有16个维修出口
So we have 16 breach exits,
所有都能从外部入口把手
all of which we can secure from outside entry.
你担心袭击
You're worried about attack,
但我们依然敞开大门做交易吗
but we're still opening the border for trade?
没错  交易一如往常不变
Yeah, trade will continue as usual.
提尔  你和罗切留下  我有话要说
Till, you and Roche stay here. I need a word.
我在那有线人
I have a source over there.
好吧  我想我们都知道是谁
All right, I think we can guess who that is.
所以你在通过交易进行交流
So you're communicating through trade.
-她还好吗  -还好  暂时还好
- Is she all right? - She's fine...for now.
她有所发现  所以我们要继续开放边境
She's onto something, which is why we have to keep the border open.
你这么担心威尔福德
You're all worried about Wilford,
但我们自己家就麻烦事一大堆
but we've got our own problems here at home.
维修工和车尾人斗得你死我活
The Breachmen and the Tailies are at each other's throats.
莱茨手指被砍掉已经过去两周了
It's been two weeks since Lights' fingers were chopped off,
但我还没找到一个嫌犯
and I still don't have a suspect--
一个正经的嫌犯
a legitimate suspect.
听着  提尔  不如你请一天假
Look, Till, why don't you take a day.
好好休息
Get some rest.
他说的对  休息一天
He's right. Take a day.
如果莱顿先生不想让乘客服务部
If Mr. Layton wants to keep Hospitality
知道他的诡计
out of his machinations,
我们也只能不让他知道我们的了
we'll just have to keep him out of ours.
有些事还是不知道为好  露丝
Some things are need to know, Ruth.
什么事  比如奥德丽是间谍吗
What things? Like Audrey is spying?
他不觉得那很冒险吗  让他们俩在一起
He doesn't think that's risky-- putting them two back together?
人们需要知道我不是昨天才出生
People need to realize I wasn't born yesterday.
当然不  女士
No, ma'am.
特里斯坦  你不再是播音员了
Tristan, you are fired from the address service.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
好了  扎拉  我们看看你的本事吧
Right, Zarah, let's see what you've got?
-我  现在吗  -看你如何应对压力
- Me? Now? - Mm, poise under pressure.
你还好吗
You all right?
我早上会犯恶心
Morning sickness.
你怎么不早说
Why didn't you say so?
你不能这样播音
You can't do announcements like that.
早上好  雪国列车
Good morning, Snowpiercer.
今天我们将攀登西藏高原
Today as we climb the Tibetan Plateau,
外面的温度是零下83摄氏度
the temperature outside is -118 degrees centigrade.
风向是西北偏北
The wind is north-northwest
风速是30至40节
at 30 to 40 knots.
乘客服务部提醒各位
Hospitality would like to remind you all
请关注今天的海拔变化
to be mindful of the change in elevation today.
靠窗的乘客
For our window watchers,
今天我们将经过拉萨
today we will be passing Lhasa,
昔日西藏的著名紫禁城
the famous forbidden city of what was formerly Tibet.
你听到了吗
Oh, did you hear that?
派克先生
Mr. Pike.
送个邀请函会死啊
A simple invite would have worked.
任何人  包括你  不经我的允许不能去三等厢
Nothing, including you, moves through Third without my permission.
如果你再
If you ever...
踏入这里一步  你就死了
Set foot up here again, you'll be dead.
我讨厌这个声音
Ugh, I hate that sound.
我知道  这是钉子
Yeah, I know. It's when the staples
订进头骨的声音
turn in against the skull.
再来一次  准备好了吗
One more--ready?
莱顿
Oh, Layton!
我的大麻生意喂饱了车尾  兄弟
My weed trade feeds the Tail, brother.
这难道不是你给我的原因之一吗
Is that not part of the reason you gave it to me?
是的  你也知道
Yes, you know it is.
是LJ  那个小变态
It was LJ, you know, the little psycho.
那孩子让我害怕  她是你教出来的
That kid scares me, and she's your cultivation.
那奥斯维勒呢
What about Osweiller?
不重要  他是匹独狼  是特伦斯
Forget about him. He's a lone wolf. It's Terence.
是特伦斯  我的兄弟  不能再这样了
It's Terence, my brother. This can't stand.
不会的  听着
It won't. Hey.
我会处理的
I will handle this.
你和赛克斯什么时候打算告诉我
When do you and Sykes plan on telling me
你们在前车密谋着什么
what you're cooking uptrain?
耐心点  亲爱的
Patience, my dear.
接下来要发生的事对每个人来说都是惊喜
What's coming will be a surprise to everybody.
这套对私人晚宴来说合适吗
Fitting for an intimate evening?
-你看上去很好  -很好
- You look fine. - Fine?
年轻女士应该有一个确定的审美观
A young woman should have a firm aesthetic opinion
或者是一个坚定的立场  不是吗
if not an outright stance, shouldn't she?
你又开始性别歧视了  达布斯
Your sexism is showing again, Dubs.
为什么你可以邀请奥德丽过来
How come you can invite Audrey over
而我不可以去见莱拉·福爵
and I can't go see Lilah Folger?
因为  亲爱的  今天是关于奥德丽
Because, my dear, today is about Audrey.
你是担心她会顶替你的地位吗
You worried she'll take your place, hm?
我担心你对我手软
I'm worried you're going soft on me.
这边请  女士
Right this way, ma'am.
奥德丽怎样帮我们夺取雪国列车
How does Audrey help us take Snowpiercer?
那就是谜团揭开的时候  艾莉珊德拉
Well, that's where you watch the mystery unfold, Alexandra.
这活对你们来说有些掉架子  不是吗
Kind of beneath you two, ain't it?
至少  你们俩在一起
Well, at least you're together.
那我自己上去了
I'll see myself up.
我们有过协议  我完全理解
We had an agreement. I get it all.
我可以和你六四分成
I can do 60/40 for you.
车尾需要这个交易  特伦斯
The Tail needs that trade, Terence.
他们靠它为生
It feeds 'em.
你知道我根本不在乎那个
You know I don't give a shit about that.
我知道
I know.
这是这些年来对你的投诉
It's got all of the complaints against you over the years.
抢劫  贩毒  敲诈勒索
Robbery, drug dealing, extortion--
我们还加了些未破的案子
we threw in some unsolved crimes.
接受协议  特伦斯  不然我就把你关起来
Take the deal, Terence, or I'll lock you up.
我一直在观察你在后面的贸易
I've been watching your trade back there, and...
我发现了点什么
I noticed something--
那个肮脏的小娃子  温妮  每次有出货的时候
that dirty, little tyke Winnie running uptrain
就会往前车跑
every time there's a shipment.
所以我就在想  你在那边有什么人
So it got me thinking-- who you got over there,
威尔福德又会对间谍
and what will Wilford do
做些什么
to a spy?
小心点  特伦斯
Careful, Terence.
我一直很小心谨慎
I'm always careful.
好的
Right.
是乔茜
It's Josie?
乔茜就是你从那边获取信息的方法
Josie's how you're getting information back there?
还有谁知道
Who else knows?
几个车尾人  罗切和提尔
A few Tailies, Roche, and Till.
就没了  但是现在  特伦斯
That's it, but now Terence
也知道了  并以此像手雷一样抵在我头上
is holding it like a grenade to my head.
嗨  快乐的准父母
Hey, happy parents to be.
我整天都在期待这个
I have been looking forward to this all day.
看  你们的孩子在这
Aha, there's your baby.
那个小点
That little dot?
你的孩子现在的大小和蓝莓差不多
Your child is roughly the size of a blueberry.
蓝莓  好久没有吃过了
Blueberry--haven't had one of those in a while.
没有蜜蜂蓝莓很难生长
Oh, well, blueberries are tough without the bees,
不过我听到蜜蜂们正在恢复
but I hear the bees are bouncing back.
说不准能赶上你的预产期
Oh, maybe in time for the due date.
我去帮你把这个打印出来
Well, I'm gonna go get that printout for you.
如果特伦斯威胁揭发乔茜
If Terence is threatening to expose Josie,
他就是在威胁我们
he's threatening us.
必须得处理他  安德烈
He needs to be dealt with, Andre.
我不是在车尾了  扎拉
I'm not in the Tail anymore, Zarah.
我不能那么做
I can't do that.
你可以批准去做
You could sanction it.
我知道你有人手可以去做
I know you have the person to do it.
就快到了
About time.
这次靠近紫禁城
This approach to the forbidden city
看起来很困难
is looking pretty hairy.
我很期待看到它
I'm looking forward to seeing it.
威尔福德不在这
Wilford's not here.
我很开心
I'm glad.
我们能相处片刻  只有我们女人
We have a moment, just us women.
-你想和我聊天  -是的
- You wanted to speak to me? - Yes.
-你妈妈和我是朋友  -但是
- Your mother and I are friends. - Well,
她和约瑟夫是敌人  那么  你算是什么
her and Joseph are enemies, so what would that make you?
中立  亲爱的
Neutral, darling.
他拿你的专辑折磨了我们一天
He tortures us with your albums all day.
这些歌真的都是在唱他吗
Are all of those songs really about him?
大部分是的
Most of 'em.
这么说你爱他
So you love him.
你爱他  这才是重点
You love him. That's the deal.
至少可以说  我和约瑟夫之间的感情很复杂
What Joseph and I have is complicated to say the least,
但如果我和他的关系
but I wouldn't be here if my connection to him
没有比我对其他人的更深  我也不会在这了
wasn't deeper than anything I've felt with anyone else.
她说得对  那是个无底洞
She's right. It's an abyss.
奥德丽是我认识的直觉最好的人
Audrey is one of the most intuitive people i've ever met.
欢迎你加入我们  老朋友
Welcome aboard, old friend.
有话要说吗  艾莉克斯
Something to add, Alex?
看着仪表数字攀升
You know, watching instruments ascend
就像是在看水煮开一样
is like watching water boil.
没办法让它们加速再快一点
You're not gonna make it go any faster.
3.6万米  没有上行线
36,000 metres and no uplink.
拜托  梅兰妮  拜托
Come on, Melanie, come on.
是她那边出问题还是我们这边
Is it her end or ours?
3.95万米  没有砰砰声
39,500, no ping.
我得在一切还来得及之前让其达到平衡
I have to level out before it's too late.
本  她可能只是遥测出问题了
Ben, she's probably just having a telemetry issue.
她会找到的
She'll find it.
她绝对不会错过上行线的
She'd never miss an uplink
除非出什么问题了
unless something was wrong.
我们最好告诉其他人
We'd better let the others know.
谢谢  谢谢大家
Thank you. Thank you so much.
大家站成一排  谢谢
Okay, line up nice and straight, thank you.
自从梅兰妮走了之后
Since Melanie's departure,
孩子们一直在谈论地球的未来
the kids have been talking a lot about the planet's future,
所以他们创造了些东西  来和整辆列车一起
so they created something to share their hope
分享他们的希望
with the entire train.
放下来  举起来  举起来
All right, time to drop it. Hold it up, hold it up.
谢谢你  梅兰妮
Thank you, Melanie!
-我们爱你  梅兰妮  -我们爱你
- We love you, Melanie. - We love you.
-我们爱你  梅兰妮  -这样可以了
- We love you, Melanie. - Okay, that's enough.
梅兰妮·卡维尔的名誉恢复了
More reputation rehabilitation for Melanie Cavill.
谢谢你们  孩子们
Thank you, children.
你们美丽的壁画会挂上整整一周
Your lovely mural will hang all week
让每个人都能看到
where everyone can see it.
我们的发射数据没问题  仪器也在运行
Our launch data checks out, and our instruments are live,
但是梅兰妮还没有联系
but Melanie hasn't made contact.
可能是任何情况  对吗
Well, that could be anything, couldn't it?
问题显然是出现在她那边
The problem appears to be on her end.
我们必须要考虑她出了意外
We have to consider that something happened to her
也许我们不会再听到她的消息
and that we might not hear from her again.
目前我们发射了11个探测器
We've launched 11 probes so far,
所幸的是
so with a little luck,
这足以建立气候模型  但是梅兰妮
that's enough to build a climate model, but Melanie...
我知道她会没事的
I know that she's okay.
每天我都能感受到她的存在
I can feel her out there every day.
明天我们回去找她
Well, we turn around for her tomorrow,
所以我们要照计划发射最后一个探测器
so we need to launch our last probe as scheduled.
绝对不能让威尔福德知道
Wilford can't get wind of this.
同意
Agreed.
我们要让他继续参与任务
We need to keep him on mission,
回去找梅兰妮
going back to get Melanie.
我们要怎么和乘客们说
And what should we tell the passengers?
他们在等着我们宣布
They're expecting an announcement.
梅兰妮是唯一维系我们团结的因素
Melanie's the one thing that's been keeping us all together.
她维系了七年  还是有影响力的
She did it for seven years. It still means something.
那我们就撒谎吧
So then we lie.
为了希望而撒的谎
A lie for hope.
这个你为之奋斗的新世界秩序
This new world order you fought for
并不向人们口中所说的那么好吧
isn't all it's cracked up to be, is it?
所有人都能获得自由
It's a free for all.
你会更想抓到威尔福德吧
You'd rather have Wilford?
我更想静观其变
I'd rather sit back and see where the chips fall.
我做不到  小奥  我没法袖手旁观
I can't do that, Oz. There's something about me.
我挺想你的  贝丝  真的
I kind of miss you, Bess. I do.
你有听说任何
You hear anything even slightly solid
关于维修工袭击车尾人的确凿消息吗
about the Breachman attacking that Tailie?
确凿消息  没有
Solid, no.
他们很厉害
I mean, they're good for it.
受雇于威尔福德  有组织
Wilford hires, organized.
那又怎样  谁都有可能
So what? Could be anyone.
回头见  提尔
See you around, Till.
恭维那两个混蛋
Compliments of those two assholes.
-敬我们伟大的工程师  -说得好
- To our great Engineer! - Here, here.
-波吉  -嗯
- Boki. - Mm-hmm?
敬我们伟大的工程师
To our great Engineer.
听着  这会造成麻烦
Hey, hey, listen, that leads to trouble.
-我巴不得呢  -跟我来
- Yeah, I'm hoping. - Come with me.
我有东西给你看
I've got something for you.
-你想拳击  -是的
- You want to spar? - Yeah.
出乎我的意料  牧师
Okay, not what I was expecting, pastor.
我在酒吧认识你  我只会去最让人意想不到的地方
Just met you in a bar. I go where I'm least expected.
你就这点能耐
Is that all you got?
我在学校里赢过很多男生
I beat a lot of boys at the academy.
我不想伤害你
I don't want to hurt you.
你在过去伤害过很多人
You hurt a lot of people in your past.
-什么  -人们伤害你
- What? - People hurt you.
你不想感受痛苦  但那不可避免
You don't want to feel pain, but it's unavoidable.
受苦是人类状态的一部分
Suffering is a part of the human condition.
你不能在不伤害人的情况下享乐  放松
You can't get to joy, to relief, without hurting--
有时伤害你自己  有时是别人
sometimes yourself, sometimes others.
你还好吗
You all right?
我在想梅兰妮
I have Melanie on my mind.
给你讲乘客服务部的事项
You know, walking you through Hospitality,
让我记起了很多事
it has me remembering all sorts of things.
你需要休息一下吗
You need a moment?
不  跟我来
No. Walk with me
我顺便在脑子里构思下如何
as I compose this announcement of false hope
给乘客们宣布虚假希望
for the passengers in my head.
我不天真  扎拉
You know, I'm not naive, Zarah--
从来不是  以后也不会
never was, never will be.
我知道掌权的人会撒谎
I know that people in power lie.
就连我也做过我感到可耻的事
Even I've done things in teal that I'm ashamed of.
为了提升乘客们的士气
Well, a white lie to lift the passengers' spirits
而说的善意谎言不包含在内
won't be one of them.
你是这列车上的领袖  露丝
You're a leader on this train, Ruth.
你的选择能产生影响
Your choices make a difference.
我需要它们能产生影响  扎拉
You know, I need them to, Zarah.
真的需要
I really do.
我记得攀登
I remember us climbing the steps
哲蚌寺的阶梯
of the Drepung Monastery right out there.
再次看到  真的很美
It's so beautiful to see again.
好难过
So sad.
都没了  伟大的城市
Yes, all gone--great cities,
宗教  完整的思想流派
religions, whole schools of thought.
外面的世界
The world out there
失去了意义
doesn't serve a purpose anymore.
谢天谢地我跟那个
Well, then, thank goodness I'm with the man
创造了唯一继续有意义的事物的人在一起
who invented the one thing that continues to matter.
只有你回到我身边它才有价值  奥德丽
It's only worth it if you're back by my side, Audrey.
那就开一瓶开胃酒  这样我好逗留久一点
Then open an aperitif so I can linger.
我肯定能找到点甜的东西
I'm sure I can find something sweet.
该死
Shit.
好美
It's so beautiful.
我们刚说到哪了
Where were we?
大爱丽丝  大爱丽丝  这里是雪国列车
Big Alice, Big Alice, this is Snowpiercer.
失陪下
Excuse me.
本  是你的鼻音吗
Ben, is that your nasally voice?
我就是来确认下
I'm just confirming.
我们今天发射了11号气球
We launched the balloon 11 today,
梅兰妮像往常一样连上了
and, uh, Melanie linked up as usual.
真令人着迷  本
Riveting stuff, Ben.
我想这就是为什么气候科学
I guess that's why climate science
一直没有受众
never really found an audience.
要看看点心有什么吗
Shall we see what's for dessert?
你应该明白
I think you get it.
所以我才在这里
Guess that's why I'm sitting here.
并不总是适合你  对吗
Doesn't really suit you, does it?
当时正好有空位
It was available.
我说这一切
I mean any of it.
管理列车
Running the train.
有些事我自己做不到
There are some things I can't do myself.
车尾想要因同类相食而吊死我
The Tail wanted to hang me for cannibalism,
你为我担保
and you vouched for me.
我知道
I know.
我发誓
And I made a vow
永远不再在战斗之外
never kill outside of combat
杀人  为了做一个
again, to be a...
做一个更好的人
to be a better man, to...
-变得更善良  -你做到了
- to have a better heart. - You have.
除了当你让我做这样的事之外
Except when you ask me to do something like this.
如果特伦斯想要利用乔茜
If Terence is going to try and use Josie
来敲诈我  那她就不安全
to blackmail me, she isn't safe.
我们不能失去那边的线人
We can't lose our source over there,
她是我们的姐妹  派克
and she's our sister, Pike.
没人会在雪国列车历史上
Ain't no scribe writing Pike's story
记录派克的故事
in the history of Snowpiercer.
车尾人的故事会流传更久  兄弟
Tailie stories live longer, brother.
你刚刚看上去很不错
You looked good in there.
-你该保持下去  -也许吧
- You should keep it up. - I might.
你之前说的那些话
Hey, that stuff you said earlier
关于人类伤害自己和别人
about humans hurting ourselves and others...
-你真的相信吗  -是的
- Do you believe it? - I do.
似乎不怎么像基督
Doesn't seem very Christlike.
你比任何人都
You know the realities
更了解这辆列车的现实状况
of this train better than anyone.
你见过人们对彼此  对自己做的事
You've seen what people do to one another, to themselves.
而一想到
And it's depressing
在世界末日我们都无法
to think that, at the end of the world,
互相善待  就令人抑郁
we can't just find a way to be good to one another.
我不这么看
I don't look at it that way.
这辆列车最近经历了很多
This train has gone through a lot recently.
人们想要指引  一个依靠的人
People want guidance, someone to look to.
不是莱顿
And that's not Layton?
我知道你跟他很亲近
I know you're close to him,
但在他的带领下我们举步维艰
but it hasn't been an easy road under his leadership.
你肯定也感受到了
You must feel it too.
酝酿着的改变
The change that's brewing.
一个领袖能妥协的次数有限
A leader can only compromise himself so many times
然后群众就会失去对他的信任
before he loses the faith of his flock.
我们得给他时间
We need to give him time.
也许吧
Possibly.
或者他是错误的领导人
Or he's the wrong shepherd.
《耶利米书》
Jeremiah...
第50章
Chapter 50
第6节
verse 6...
我的百姓作了迷失的羊
"My people have been lost sheep.
牧人使他们走差路
Their shepherds have led them astray"...
使他们转到山上
"Turning them away on the mountains"...
他们从大山走到小山
"From mountain to hill, they have gone"...
竟忘了安歇之处
"They have forgotten their fold."
这是什么
And what the hell is this?
我需要公平
I need this to be fair.
你来杀我  你还想要公平
You come here to kill me, and you want it to be fair?
这是车尾的习惯
It's a Tail thing.
奥斯维勒
Osweiller!
他不在
He's not here.
他们都去散步了
They all took a walk.
好吧  等下
All right, man, hold on.
听着
Listen...
莱顿提出六四分  我可以接受
Layton offered 60/40, right? I can live with that.
我也不会说出
And I won't say a thing
他女友在大爱丽丝上做间谍的事
about his girl over on Big Alice.
拜托  特伦斯  我这是出于好意
Please, Terence, I'm giving you this courtesy.
快速安静地搞定  没人乱跑
Just do this quickly, quietly, and no one comes running.
不要
No!
我本想要你带着尊严死
I wanted you to do this with honor!
-等等  你不用  -安静死去
- Wait, wait, you don't--wait! - To do this quietly!
你这么做是对的  安德烈
You did the right thing, Andre.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
嗯
Yeah.
晚上好  雪国列车
Good evening, Snowpiercer.
今天早些时候  在高空  我们又一个气象气球
Earlier today, high above us, another of our weather balloons
和卡维尔工程师建立了联系
made contact with Engineer Cavill
她独自一人在外面
out there on her own,
给我们前方的路照明
a lone spark lighting the way forward.
在这辆列车上
On this train,
我们对绝望都不陌生
none of us are strangers to despair,
所以我们应该在胜利的时候好好庆祝
so we should celebrate these victories when they come.
我们必须坚守我们的任务  我们的愿景
We must hold fast to our mission, our vision,
还有我们自己
and ourselves.
所以
So...
在我们准备回去找她的同时
as we prepare to turn around and return to her...
我们一起为卡维尔工程师
Let us all say a prayer for Engineer Cavill
以及未来能在雪国列车之外生活祈祷
and our dreams of a life one day beyond Snowpiercer.
把这些喝完就开始
All right, down the hatch with these we go.
手术要多久
How long does the procedure take?
大概一小时
Roughly an hour.
趁我还没忘我得把这个记下来
Oh, I gotta jot this down before I forget.
好了  晚安
There we are. Nighty night.
那个赛克斯
That Sykes...
她最近带来的都是坏消息
she only brings bad news these days.
我不喜欢她今天的来访
I did not appreciate her visit today.
血  组织
Blood, tissue...
桶  楼梯  光
Bucket, stairs, lights.
-威尔福德一催再催  -我们不会输的
- Wilford pushes and pushes. - We won't lose.
-她动了吗  -我没注意到
- Did she move? - I didn't notice.
光
Lights.
按钮
Button.
血
Blood.
-今晚就开始了  -嗯  维修工
- It's starting tonight. - Mm, the Breachmen.
他这么早就利用他们
He's using them so early.
真可惜
It's a shame.
我们可能会早早失去一些好实验对象
We could lose some good subjects too soon.
我看到你把药扔了
I saw you ditch your meds.
你做手术的时候并没有昏过去  对吗
You weren't knocked out during that procedure, were you?
不知道你在说什么
Don't know what you're talking about.
给我
Give them to me.
你要告诉他们吗
Are you gonna tell them?
我希望你知道你在做什么
I hope you know what you're doing.
边境很快就关了  你不必离开
Border's closing soon. You don't have to go.
留下来陪我
Stay with me.
我跟以前不一样了
I'm not the same person anymore.
一样的  你还是从前的你
You are. You are the same person.
你没听我说  我不会被你击溃
You're not hearing me. I won't be broken by you.
如果我们要继续下去  你得让我击垮你
And if we're gonna do this, you need to let me break you.
我觉得这不可能
I don't think that's possible--
表面下有太多的冰
too much ice under the surface.
如果你不放我进去
So if you won't let me in,
你就不能改善列车
you can't change for the good of the train,
那我在这干什么
then what am I doing here?
奥德丽
Audrey...
你比任何人都了解我  你也了解莱顿
you know me better than anyone, and you know Mr. Layton.
你觉得最后谁会赢
Who do you think will come out on top?
约瑟夫  你在计划什么
Joseph, what are you planning?
嘘  我希望在我把车夺回来后你能在我身边
Shh, I want you by my side when I take her back.
留下来陪我
Stay, stay with me.
你不肯承认
You won't admit it to yourself,
但没有我你如同行尸走肉
but you're only half alive without me.
我也一样
It's the same for me.
在一起时我们充满刺激
Together we're electric,
每条神经都在燃烧
every nerve on fire.
留下来  奥德丽
Stay with me, Audrey.
到了  老大
This one's here, boss.
你可以过去了  谢谢
You're clear to pass. Thank you.
让开  免费贸易来了
Make way. Free trade coming through.
好的  让开
All right, out of the way.
泰尼  别碰  你得等着
Tiny, get your hands off it. You have to wait.
今晚  维修工
东西快运完了  还是不见奥德丽
Well, that's almost all of it and still no Audrey.
联系罗切  叫他来维修车间见我
Call Roche; tell him to meet me at Muscle Breach.
为什么  怎么了
Why? What's going on?
你处理完交易  接回奥德丽
Just finish up trade, get Audrey back,
第一时间关门
close the door ASAP.
让开  波吉
Ah, hey, step away from there, Boki!
-放开我  你疯了吗  -你的朋友呢
- Get off of me. You crazy? - Where are your friends?
-附近  -他们在哪
- Around. - Where are they?
我们知道你们在替威尔福德密谋
We know you're plotting for Wilford.
你在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
不不不
No, no, no, no.
-沃德尔夫人  -奥德丽
- Ms. Wardell. - Audrey.
那边什么情况
What on Earth is going on over there?
恐怕我也不清楚  威尔福德先生
I'm afraid I'm not quite sure, Mr. Wilford.
你做了什么  约瑟夫
What have you done, Joseph?
选择仍在你手上  奥德丽
The choice is still yours, Audrey.
你呢  露丝
How about you, Ruth?
我知道你一直很想过来看看
I know you've been dying to visit.
在门关上前快过来吧
Step over before the doors close.
我不能那么做  先生
I can't do that now, sir.
奥德丽
Audrey?
奥德丽  奥德丽
Audrey? Audrey?
晚安  露丝
Good night, Ruth.
我希望一切都好
I do hope everything's all right.